SANDRA POLANIA-REYES

E: sa.polania@javeriana.edu.co http://spolaniareyes.github.io/

P: +1 (734) 277-1984

Pontificia Universidad Javeriana

Cra. 7 No. 40 B-36

Ed. Jorge Hoyos Vásquez S.J., Piso 7

Bogotá, Colombia

RESEARCH AND TEACHING FIELDS

PRIMARY Experimental Economics SECONDARY Behavioral Economics
Applied Microeconomics Impact Evaluation
Development Economics Microeconometrics

PROFESIONAL APPOINTMENTS

2017 Assistant Professor, Department of Economics, Pontificia Universidad Javeriana. Bogota, Colombia

2017-18 Visiting Fellow. Kellogg Institute for International Studies and Centre for Ethics and Culture. University of Notre Dame, IN, US

2016-17 Post-doctoral Fellow. Department of Economics and Centre for Ethics and Culture. University of Notre Dame, Notre Dame, IN, USA

EDUCATION

2015	Ph.D Economics	University College London – UCL, London, UK
2015	Ph.D. Economics (Economia Politica)	University of Siena, Siena, IT
2005	M.A. Economics	University of Los Andes, Bogotá, Colombia
2003	B.A. Economics and Anthropology	University of Los Andes, Bogotá, Colombia

FELLOWSHIPS

2017	Kellogg Institute Visiting Fellowship. Keough School of Global Affairs, Kellogg Institute for
	International Studies. University of Notre Dame, USA.
2016	Center for Ethics and Culture Postdoctoral Fellowship, University of Notre Dame, USA
2010, 2012	University College London annually Studentships
2008, 2010	Doctoral scholarship for mobility, University of Siena, Italy
2009	Graduate Research Scholarship, University College London, UK
2007-2011	Doctoral Scholarship, University of, Siena, Italy
2007	Colfuturo Scholarship Loan for graduate studies, Colombia
2003	Fee waiver for the Master in Economics, University of Los Andes, Bogota, Colombia

GRANTS

- 2014 Experimental Social Science Laboratory, Institute of Business and Economic Research. UC Berkeley. Leading by non-example: do leader's social preferences matter for cooperation? Co-PI D. Echeverry,
- 2007 IADB Grant. Building Trust for Good Governance: Field Experiments in Latin America. The Latin American Research Network, Co-PI Prof. JC Cárdenas and N. Candelo (Project RG-T1258)
- 2006 IADB Grant. Discrimination in the Provision of Social Services to the Poor: A Field Experimental Study. Latin America Research Network, Co-PI JC Cárdenas, A. Gaviria, R. Sethi, N. Candelo (Project R-544)

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Spring 2018 Economics of Collective Action. Pontificia Universidad Javeriana. Department of Economics.

Spring 2015 Experimental and Behaviorl Economics on evaluation and design of social interventions.

Corpovisionarios, Bogota, Colombia

Graduate Student Instructor. Department of Economics, UCL, London, UK
Spring 2011, Spring 2012
Experimental Economics
Winter 2011
Microeconomics

Teaching Assistant. Department of Economics, University of Los Andes, Bogotá, Colombia.

Spring 2007 Introduction to the Colombian Economy

Spring 2005, Fall 2005, Spring 2006, Fall 2006

Spring 2005, Fall 2005, Spring 2006, Fall 2006

Fall 2004

Introduction to the Colombian Economy
Introduction to Microeconomics
Intermediate Microeconomics
Graduate Experimental Economics

PUBLICATIONS

Refereed Journal Articles

- 2015 "Building social capital: Conditional cash transfers and cooperation". With Orazio Attanasio and Luca Pellerano *Journal of Economic Behavior and Organization*. 118, October, 22–39.
- 2012 "Economic incentives and social preferences: substitutes or complements?" With Sam Bowles. *Journal of Economic Literature*. 50, June, 368-425.
- 2009 "Building trust? Conditional cash transfer programs and social capital". With Orazio Attanasio and Luca Pellerano. *Fiscal Studies*, 30, 139–177.
- 2005 "Social Capital and Household Income in Urban Colombia". *Revista Desarrollo y Sociedad*. University of Los Andes. 56. September, 221-284.

Book chapters

- 2009 Discrimination in the Provision of Social Services to the Poor: A Field Experimental Study. With Juan Camilo Cárdenas, Natalia Candelo, Alejandro Gaviria and Rajiv Sethi. Chapter 3. In: *Discrimination in Latin America: an Economic perspective*. Edited by Hugo Ñopo, Alberto Chong, Andrea Moro. LADF Series World Bank.
- 2008 What Extent Do Latin Americans Trust and Cooperate? Field Experiments on Social Exclusion in Six Latin American Countries. With Juan Camilo Cárdenas, Sebastian Calónico, Natalia Candelo, Alberto Chong and Hugo Ñopo. In: *IADB IPES 2008 Report: Outsiders? The Changing Patterns of Exclusion in Latin America and the Caribbean* (David Rockefeller/Inter-American Development Bank). Chap. 7.

Manuscripts in preparation

Coordination as Unintended Benefit: Lab-in-the-Field Evidence from a Conditional Cash Transfer Program Prosocial behavior, Heterogeneity and Incentives: Experimental Evidence from the local commons in Colombia.

Work pays: different benefits of a workfare program in Colombia. With Orazio Attanasio, Costas Meguir (Yale University), Marcos Vera-Hernandez (UCL) and Arthur Alik (University of Toulouse).

Identification of Other-Regarding Preferences: Evidence from a Common Pool Resource Game in Colombia. With David Echeverry (University of California Berkeley).

Motivating Teamwork in Organizations: Lab-in-the-Field Evidence on Cooperation and Social Recognition. Leading by non-example: do leader's social preferences matter for cooperation? Experimental evidence from Colombia.

Are Public Officials Less Pro-Social? An Artefactual Field Experiment in Colombia. With Natalia Candelo, Juan Camilo Cárdenas, Alejandro Gaviria.

Other manuscripts

Parental generosity and early child development: an experimental approach. I designed an economic experiment to measure parents' willingness to invest in their children's human capital.

Helping the Helpers: Altruism as A Rational Choice of Donors to A Students Voluntary Organization. With Juan Camilo Cárdenas and Miguel Espinosa 2009. Working paper CEDE (30). UAndes.

Pasos metodológicos de un diseño experimental para medir capital social y acción colectiva en seis ciudades latinoamericanas [Methodological steps for an experimental design to measure social capital and collective action in six Latinamerican cities] With Natalia Candelo. 2008. Working paper CEDE, 37. University of Los Andes

Darwin in the experimental lab: between and within group competition effects on human behavior. I use a Public Goods game we conducted in 2007 with the sample of Cárdenas, et al. 2008 (above)

SELECTED RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Corpovisionarios, Bogotá D.C., Colombia

2015 – to date Research Consultant

Implementation of Artefactual Field Experiments and impact evaluation of behavioral interventions with private organizations.

Institute of Fiscal Studies, London, UK

2007–2008 Project Manager, Experimental Leader, Field Work Coordinator.

With O. Attanasio. Implementing an Artefactual Field Experiment of the effect of a Conditional Cash Transfer on social preferences.

Department of Economics, University of Los Andes, Bogota, Colombia

2006–2007 Project Manager, Field Work Coordinator and experimental Leader.

With JC Cárdenas on designing and implementing economic experiments on social and risk preferences in Argentina, Colombia, Costa Rica, Peru, Venezuela and Uruguay and on social preferences to measure discrimination in the provision of social services to the poor in Bogotá, Colombia.

2004-2007 Research Assistant.

With JC Cárdenas on designing and implementing economic experiments with a dynamic component to observe the rules in common dilemmas and sustaining inclusive Collective Action that Links across Economic and Ecological Scales in upper watersheds.

INVITED PRESENTATIONS AND CONFERENCES

- Bogota Experimental Economics Conference, Universidad del Rosario, Central Bank of Colombia (Medellin), McGrath Institute for Church Life, Kellogg Institute for International Studies
- Fall Ethics Conference University of Notre Dame, Krannert School of Management Purdue University, First Latin-American Workshop on Experimental and Behavioural Social Sciences (LAWEBESS), Advances in Field Experiments (UChicago), UC Berkeley, University of Los Andes, University of Massachusetts-Amherst, University of Notre Dame Economics, Pontifical Xavierian University, NYU CESS 10th Annual Experimental Political Science Conference.
- 2016 Advances in Field Experiments (UChicago), University of Notre Dame.
- 2015 BABEEW (Bay Area Behavioral and Experimental Economics Workshop), University of San Francisco, UC Berkeley, Institute of Fiscal Studies.
- 2014 BABEEW (Bay Area Behavioral and Experimental Economics Workshop), Georg-August-Universität Göttingen.
- 2013 University of Los Andes.
- 2012 European Network for Training in Economic Research Jamboree, University of Barcelona. University of Oxford (International Development)
- 2010 The Evolution of Cooperation and Trading (TECT) Central European University, Budapest. University of Konstanz.
- 2009 ECORE, Université Libre de Bruxelles, Université Catholique de Louvain, Centre for Research in the Economics of Development CRED, University of Namur. CESifo's 10th Venice Summer Institute. University of Siena. London School of Economics.
- 2008 German Federal Agency for Nature Conservation GTZ, Vilm; University of Zurich.
- National University of Colombia, Externado University of Colombia, University of Los Andes, Pontificia Universidad Javeriana, Latin American and Caribbean Economic Association (LACEA).

OTHER CONTRIBUTIONS

- 2017 University Life fellow. McGrath Institute for Church Life. University of Notre Dame, IN, US
- 2018 CORE's The Economy. http://www.core-econ.org/ 2017. Chapter 17. Spanish Translation. In process.
- Collaboration on the website www.wealthometer.org. Tool to raise awareness in the wider public, illustrating the main tradeoffs when thinking about taxing wealth. Spanish translation.

- 2010 Microeconomics: Behavior, Institutions, and Evolution, by S. Bowles. Princeton University Press, 2004. Chapter 14. Spanish Translation. November.
- 2008 Policies Designed for Self-Interested Citizens May Undermine 'The Moral Sentiments': Evidence from Economic Experiments. Science 320: 5883 (June 20). Supporting Online Material.

DISCIPLINARY SERVICE

Referee Economic Journal, Journal of Public Economics, European Economic Review, Journal of Development Economics, Scandinavian Journal of Economics, Journal of Economic Methodology, Ecological Economics, Revista Desarrollo y Sociedad, Lecturas de Economía, International Review of Economics, Oxford Economic Papers, Journal of Economic Behavior and Organization, Journal of Economic Psychology, Journal of Behavioral and Experimental Economics, American Political Science Review, Journal: Journal of Environmental Economics and Management.

COMMUNITY-BASED ENGAGEMENT

2018 to date	Consultant, Colombian Conference of Catholic Bishops. Family and Life unit.
2014 - 2015	Natural Family Planning advisor, Diocese of Oakland, CA, US
2013 - 2015	Catechist, St. Ambrose Catholic Church, Albany, CA, US
2009 - 2012	Volunteer, London Jesuit Volunteers, London, UK
2003 - 2012	Coordinator, Fundación Bella Flor, Bogotá, Colombia

LANGUAGES English (Fluent), Spanish (native speaker), Italian (Intermediate), French (Beginner)

PROFESSIONAL Stata, R, Matlab, Z-tree, C++, O-tree **SKILLS**

PROFESSIONAL American Economic Association, Economic Science Association, Berkeley Initiative for Transparency of Social Sciences – BITTS, Catholic Research Economists Discussion **AFFILIATIONS** Organization – CREDO

REFERENCES

Orazio Attanasio Samuel Bowles Department of Economics Behavioral Science Program

University College London Santa Fe Institute London WC1E 6BT, United Kingdom 1399 Hyde Park Rd, Santa Fe, NM 87501

E: o.attanasio@ucl.ac.uk E: bowles@santafe.edu

Juan Camilo Cárdenas Syngjoo Choi Department of Economics Department of Economics Seoul National University Universidad de Los Andes Gwanak Gu, Seoul, South Korea

Carrera 1 Nº 18A-70, Bogotá, Colombia E: syngjoo@gmail.com

E: jccarden@uniandes.edu.co